Hatten sich die Menschen in Nahal Oz vor dem 7. Oktober daran gewöhnt, unter ständiger Bedrohung zu leben?
Before October 7, yes.
Yes,
We got used to it.
It was something,
I cannot say "got used to it" because
it always escalated,
so every time you think,
"Okay, this is the worst that can get."...
At a certain point
we realize that it always escalates.
If you look at the years, let's say from 2000 to today,
you will see the escalation
very, very clearly,
and it’s a very steep one.
So I used to feel
safe here because of all the means that I told you,
and I even thought that it doesn’t matter...
The logic of my head was that
"Everywhere you go in Israel, there's terror."
So, I either give up my rights to live where I was
originated,
or I accept it.